<ttyml lang="en">
    <head>
        <title>Linux</title>
    </head>
    <body>
        <p>
            <b>Linux</b>
            <i>(/ˈliːnʊks/ (listen) LEE-nuuks or /ˈlɪnʊks/ LIN-uuks)</i> is a family of open-source <a handle="unixlike" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unix-like">Unix-like</a> operating systems based on the Linux kernel, an operating system kernel first released on September 17, 1991, by <ln handle="linus" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linus_Torvalds">Linus Torvalds</a>. Linux is typically packaged as a Linux distribution, which includes the kernel and supporting system software and libraries, many of which are provided by the <a handle="gnu" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GNU_Project">GNU Project</a>. Many Linux distributions use the word "Linux" in their name, but the Free Software Foundation uses the name <i>"GNU/Linux"</i> to emphasize the importance of GNU software, causing some controversy.
        </p>
        <section depth="0">History of Linux</section>
        <p>
            Linux began in 1991 as a personal project by Finnish student Linus Torvalds: <b>to create a new free operating system kernel</b>. The resulting Linux kernel has been marked by constant growth throughout its history. Since the initial release of its source code in 1991, it has grown from a small number of C files under a license prohibiting commercial distribution to the 4.15 version in 2018 with more than 23.3 million lines of source code, not counting comments, under the <i>GNU General Public License v2</i>.
        </p>
        <section depth="1">Precursors</section>
        <p>
        The <a handle="unix" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unix">Unix</a> operating system was conceived and implemented in 1969, at <a handle="bells" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bell_Labs">AT&amp;T's Bell Labs</a>, in the United States by Ken Thompson, Dennis Ritchie, Douglas McIlroy, and Joe Ossanna. First released in 1971, Unix was written entirely in <a handle="assemb" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Assembly_language">assembl language</a>, as was common practice at the time. In 1973, in a key pioneering approach, it was rewritten in the <a handle="clang" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C_(programming_language)">C programming language</a> by Dennis Ritchie (with the exception of some hardware and I/O routines). The availability of a high-level language implementation of Unix made its porting to different computer platforms easier.
        </p>
        <section depth="0">Linux distributions</section>
        <p>
        A Linux distribution[a] (often abbreviated as distro) is an operating system made from a software collection that includes the Linux kernel, and often a package management system. Linux users usually obtain their operating system by downloading one of the <a handle="distro" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linux_distribution">Linux distributions</a>, which are available for a wide variety of systems ranging from embedded devices (for example, OpenWrt) and personal computers (for example, Linux Mint) to powerful supercomputers (for example, Rocks Cluster Distribution).
        </p>
        <section depth="1">List of Linux distributions by package manager</section>
        <section depth="2">RPM</section>
        <ul>
            <li>Red Hat Enterprise Linux</li>
            <li>Fedora</li>
            <li>CentOS</li>
        </ul>
        <section depth="2">APT</section>
        <ul>
            <li>Debian</li>
            <li>Ubuntu</li>
            <li>Kali Linux</li>
            <li>Raspbian</li>
        </ul>
        <section depth="2">Pacman</section>
        <ul>
            <li>Arch Linux</li>
            <li>Manjaro</li>
        </ul>
    </body>
</ttyml>
